PROLOGUE NARRATOR:
Over the hills and far away...
[TELETUBBIES THEME PLAYING]
... Teletubbies come to play.
NARRATOR: One.
TINKY WINKY: One.
- NARRATOR: Two.
- Two!
- NARRATOR: Three.
- Three!
NARRATOR: Four!
- DIPSY: Four!
- [TELETUBBIES GIGGLING]
NARRATOR: And the Teletubbies love each other very much.
TELETUBBIES: Aw.
Big hug.
[SQUEALS]
- [BIRDS CHIRPING]
- [SIREN BLARING]
[UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING ON TV]
- [MUFFLED BANGING]
- WOMAN 1: It's not allowed.
Why did you take so long?
They're not coming by.
WOMAN 2: Doesn't matter, it doesn't matter!
WOMAN 1: Where are the others?
They were right behind me.
NARRATOR:
Time for Teletubbies.
WOMAN 2: Let's take all the kids in one car.
NARRATOR:
Time for Teletubbies.
- [GIRL PROTESTING]
- Sit here. Sit!
Auntie, what's going on?
Jimmy, sit still, keep quiet,
and do not move from this spot.
WOMAN 1: We have got to get the kids into the car!
JIMMY'S AUNTY:
What were you doing?
- I told you to hurry up!
- MAN 1: For God's sake!
TELETUBBIES: Uh-oh!
[MUFFLED THUMPING
AND COMMOTION]
- GIRL 1: Jimmy?
- [MUFFLED SCRAPING]
TELETUBBIES: Uh-oh!
- [MUFFLED THUMP]
- GIRL 2: What is that?
[THUMPING AND COMMOTION STOP]
NARRATOR: Where have the Teletubbies gone?
[GIRLS WHIMPERING
AND SNIFFLING QUIETLY]
Dad?
- [SINGING ON TV] Tinky Winky
- Tinky Winky
Dipsy
[GROWLING AND SNARLING]
[GIRLS SCREAMING]
Jimmy, run.
- Mum?
- Run! Run!
[SCREAMING]
[UPLIFTING SURREAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
- [SNARLS]
- JIMMY'S MOTHER: Run!
Run! Jimmy, run!
Go!
[SNARLS]
JIMMY: Dad! Dad!
[UPLIFTING SURREAL
MUSIC CONTINUING]
Dad!
[GROWLING]
JIMMY'S FATHER: Jimmy.
JIMMY: Dad.
Dad, what's happening?
Nothing that hasn't been most perfectly foretold.
I'm so scared, Dad.
I think Mum and sis might be dead.
Oh, no, son.
Not dead.
- Saved.
- [INFECTED SNARLING]
For this is a glorious day.
The day of judgment.
[MUFFLED GROWLING]
[WINDOWS THUMPING]
Here, my son.
Keep this with you always.
Have faith.
Yes.
- [GROWLING]
- Yes.
Yes, my children!
Yes!
[SNARLING]
[UPLIFTING SURREAL
MUSIC CONTINUING]
Yes!
Father,
why have you forsaken me?
[SNARLING]
[WHIMPERING]
[PANTING]
[WIND WHISTLING]
[MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
MAN: It's your big day, Spike.
Up you get.
- [ROOSTER CROWS]
- [UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING]
[ROOSTER CROWS]
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC CONTINUES]
See ya later.
[FOOD SIZZLING]
MAN: Got your torch?
Jumper, whistle...
water bottle?
Here y'are.
Got your knife?
Good lad.
Put that away.
We're having bacon?
For breakfast?
Dave and Rosey brought it round last night.
Where's yours?
Had some already, while I was cooking.
Yeah, right.
Spikey.
It's all yours.
[SCREAMING]
[OBJECTS CLATTERING]
[WHIMPERS]
[SIGHS]
I'll go see to your mum.
You finish up.
Put your plate on the side.
[MAN SIGHS]
I'm coming, love.
Here y'are, love.
What's the matter, what's up?
WOMAN: Jamie...
JAMIE: You've got to ride it out, love.
- You gotta stay here and rest.
- WOMAN: Oh, I can't. No.
Oh, Spikey.
Hiya, Mum.
SPIKE'S MOTHER: Oh, me baby.
You know,
I didn't mean to make a fuss.
- It's me head. It's...
- SPIKE: It's okay.
SPIKE'S MOTHER:
It's just pounding.
Oh, why don't you tell me how school was today?
I haven't been to school, Mum.
It's the morning.
Is it?
JAMIE: Uh, yeah,
it's the morning, and, uh...
Isla...
d'you remember?
Spike's not going to school today.
ISLA: Why not?
Is it the weekend already?
JAMIE: Nah, it's Friday.
ISLA: So why isn't he going to school?
We spoke about this.
Few times.
Spoke about what, Jamie?
JAMIE: Me and Spike are going out.
It's his first time.
ISLA: First time?
Do you mean you're going off the island,
to the mainland?
- Yeah.
- ISLA: What?
JAMIE: Isla.
What the fuck are you talking about?
JAMIE: All right.
Don't swear. Come on.
[SHOUTS] Have you gone fucking crazy?
He's a fucking baby!
- SPIKE: Mum...
- He's twelve.
Are you trying to kill our fucking baby, you cunt?
Spike, will you go back downstairs, please?
You crazy fucking sick baby-murderer.
No, Dad, you go down.
- If me dad was still here...
- JAMIE: No, I'm telling you.
...he'd skin you alive, baby-murderer!
JAMIE: It'll be better if...
All right!
- Cunt!
- All right. Isla,
- it's all right.
- Cunt!
- All right. He'll be fine.
- Cunt! [WHIMPERING]
- SPIKE: Mum...
- No.
- It's me.
- [GASPS]
ISLA: Spike... Spikey.
Oh, what's going on? I'm hot.
Why... Why am I feeling so hot?
It's just the weather, Mum.
ISLA: So hot.
- It's all right.
- [ISLA SIGHS]
I got you some breakfast.
It's a bit of bacon.
Eat a bit when you feel like it.
Are you off?
- Yeah.
- Where?
- School.
- Oh.
[EXHALES]
Okay, Spikey.
Oh, I love you.
I love you, too, Mum.
Morning, kiddo.
Sam.
Just restrung this for you.
Did it need a restring?
Nope. Did it for my own sake, really.
He'll be fine, Sam.
Have a draw, son.
Feel the weight.
Hold it.
No shake at all.
Strong lad.
[CLEARS THROAT]
Howay then, son. Let's go.
[PEOPLE CHATTERING]
MAN: [LAUGHS] All right. All right.
I'll see you tonight.
- Lives are at stake.
- Cheers, lads.
- MAN 1: Go on, Jamie!
- Good luck, Spike.
Glad you're getting on now,
Spike.
MAN 2: Go on, Spike!
You go well, lad.
[CROWD CHEERING]
This is from Mum.
- Thanks, Betty.
- Your big party tonight,
our Spike. Don't be late!
Bring him back safe, yeah?
GIRL: Come on, Jamie!
[MOANING]
WOMAN: Look after him, Jamie!
MAN 3: Good luck, Spike.
All right, Jacob.
JAMIE: Look at that, Spike.
You got the whole leadership committee.
You just smile and be polite.
WOMAN: Had to see you off.
We're all excited for you.
Even though you know
I feel he's a bit young.
Fourteen or fifteen is more in keeping with practice.
He's ready, Jenny.
Go on, lad.
JENNY: You know the rules of our community, Spike.
If you leave, you can come back.
But if you don't come back,
no one is permitted to go and find you.
There are no rescues.
No exceptions.
It was something we learned the hard way...
On account of all the people we lost in the past.
So once you walk onto that mainland,
you're on your own.
You understand?
Yes, Jenny.
You seen anything this morning, Ant?
Nothing.
Fully quiet.
All clear?
All clear.
Open up for them.
Good lad.
[WIND WHISTLING]
ANTHONY: Mind how you go, lads. Don't miss the tide.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
TAYLOR HOLMES: [ON RECORDING]
Seven, six, eleven, five,
nine-and-twenty mile today
Four, eleven, seventeen,
thirty-two the day before
Boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up and down again!
There's no discharge in the war!
So, what's this, Spike?
SPIKE: It's the causeway.
JAMIE: Talk us through it.
SPIKE: It's the only way to the mainland.
But we can only get here in low tide.
In high tide,
the sea covers it.
JAMIE: Can we swim it
in high tide?
SPIKE: No.
The sea has a current.
It'll push us past the island and pull us out to sea,
and we'll drown.
HOLMES: Don't, don't, don't,
don't look at what's in front of you...
Boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up and down again
Men, men, men, men,
men go mad with watchin' em...
We'll have four hours before high tide.
Are we doing this?
Can't go back now, Dad.
Why?
Everyone'll think I'm soft.
[CHUCKLES]
Aye, they will.
Can't have that, can we? [CHUCKLES]
Come on, then. [LAUGHS]
HOLMES: Count, count, count,
count the bullets
in the bandoliers.
If your eyes drop,
they will get atop of you!
Boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up and down again
There's no discharge in the war!
JAMIE: This is where we get all the fuel.
You'll be working here one day.
HOLMES: Ain't so bad by day
because o' company,
But night brings long
strings o' forty thousand million
Boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up and down again.
SPIKE: It's so big.
- [SIGHS]
- If we kept walking,
would we get to a place where you can't see the sea?
[CHUCKLES] Wey aye.
You'll walk for days or weeks without seeing the coast.
There's nothing out there,
Spikey.
Nowhere to aim for.
There's other villages.
Aye, but none have anything we don't have.
And we stay out the towns and villages.
HOLMES: I have marched
- six weeks...
- JAMIE: Howay.
HOLMES:...in hell an' certify
It is not fire,
devils, dark, or anything,
but boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up an' down again.
[SOFT SNARLING AND GRUNTING]
- Try, try, try...
- [SNARLING]
...try to think of something different
Oh, my God,
keep me from going lunatic!
Boots, boots, boots, boots,
moving up and down again!
There's no discharge in the war!
[SOFT MOANING]
There, look, look, look, look, look, look.
Slow-Low.
Not fast.
Doesn't mean they aren't dangerous.
And if there's one visible,
probably a couple more in the trees.
Your bow
isn't strong enough for the chest.
You need to hit it right in the neck.
Okay, Dad.
JAMIE: You scared?
Only a little bit.
Are you?
No. I'm good.
You like this range?
SPIKE: I think so.
Let's go get your first kill.
[SLURPING AND COOING]
Get him in your sight.
Calculate for wind.
All right.
He's yours.
Anything that comes out after him is mine.
Send when ready.
[SCREECHES]
Send it.
[SQUEALING]
[CHOKING, WHEEZING]
[WHINING]
[SHRIEKS]
[WHIMPERING]
SPIKE: Dad!
BOY 1: Get in here!
BOY 2: Hey!
Beautiful kill, Spike.
You feel good?
Yeah, I think so.
JAMIE: Aye, you should.
I'm proud of ya.
Now come on, we gotta move.
The screaming would have alerted
the other infected in the area.
Go on. Let's keep going. [LAUGHS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[FOOTFALLS RUMBLING]
They're amazing.
JAMIE: They're beautiful.
Here.
Check this out.
Good lad.
[LIQUID DRIPPING]
[DOOR CREAKS]
- [FOX YELPS]
- Shit.
[SPIKE PANTING]
It's always worth looking around for summat useful.
People would have searched this place a hundred times,
but you never know.
[PIANO KEYS RATTLE]
Fuckin' hell.
[CHUCKLING] Oh.
SPIKE: Are these useful?
Nah. Got plenty of that.
But this is.
What is it?
A frisbee.
You never seen a frisbee before?
Aw, it's great.
You're gonna love it.
- [HIGH-PITCHED CRY]
- [GASPING]
[CAWING]
[CROW CRIES]
[LIQUID DRIPPING]
Come here, son.
[GASPS]
Don't look away, Spike.
- Dad, please.
- Spike!
Do as I tell ya.
There's a lesson for you here.
[COUGHS]
[MUFFLED SCREAM]
[MUFFLED GROWLING]
What happened to him?
Looks like he got tied up and left for the infected.
And now he's infected.
He's infected?
[MUFFLED SNARLING]
JAMIE: Aye.
Why would anyone do that?
JAMIE: Maybe a punishment.
Maybe a warning.
There are strange people on the mainland.
Roaming.
That's why our home is so precious.
Is that the lesson?
No.
- Kill it.
- [SNARLING CONTINUES]
The more you kill, the easier it gets.
[SIGHS]
Don't feel bad about it.
The infection takes away their minds.
[SNARLS]
It's got no mind, it's got no soul.
Spike.
Kill the bloody thing.
Kill it!
What are you waiting for,
Spike?
Now, son!
Spike, finish it!
For Christ's sake, Spike, fuckin' kill it!
[GASPING]
Good lad.
[HYMNAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SINGING] Abide with me
Fast falls the eventide
The darkness deepens
Lord, with me abide
Where is death's sting?
- Head. Heart. Draw...
- Where, grave, thy victory?
I triumph still
Release.
If Thou abide...
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[FLIES BUZZING]
JAMIE: There's another kill here if we're lucky.
Come on.
JAMIE: Oh.
This wasn't Slow-Lows.
This were the fast ones, Spikey.
[GAGS]
You smell that? [LAUGHS]
It's the intestines.
I weirdly like it. [ECHOING]
[FLIES BUZZING]
Dad. [BREATHING HEAVILY]
Dad.
[GRUNTS]
- [EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [PANTING AND SNARLING]
[LOW GROWLING]
What?
An Alpha did that. [BREATHING HEAVILY]
This way, Spike. Come on.
Spike! Move it!
We're going back?
Aye. Got your kills, that's what we came for.
Won't it look like we left early?
Don't talk, Spikey.
Just keep your eyes peeled.
[LEAVES RUSTLING]
[PANTING]
Looks clear.
Let's go.
- [SOFT GROWL]
- [JAMIE SHUSHING]
[DISTANT CRY]
Stay really still.
[DISTANT YELLING AND GROWLING]
[SNARLING]
[GRUNTING AND HOOTING]
JAMIE: Alpha.
Fuck.
Get back to the trees.
Get back, let's go.
Dad!
[ALPHA ROARS]
[INFECTED SHRIEKING
AND SNARLING]
Let's go!
[DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING]
Move, move.
Keep moving.
Let's go, let's go!
Here, defense.
Get your breath back.
I'll take the first,
- you take the second.
- Yeah.
Slow your breathing.
Slow it down.
[YELPS]
Shit!
[SPIKE HYPERVENTILATING]
Go! Move, move, move!
Just go!
Fuck!
Right, two-man drill. Defense!
Right. Shoot!
Head and heart.
Head and heart, Spike.
Get in there.
Go up!
[GROWLING]
- Go on, son!
- SPIKE: Come on, Dad!
Where?
Shit.
Da, what...?
JAMIE: The loft!
Check the loft!
Oi. Come here.
Go on.
SPIKE: I can't get back up.
- Oh, fuck.
- Dad! Dad!
JAMIE: Push!
JAMIE: Oh, fuck.
[INFECTED SHRIEKING]
Fuckin' hell.
[JAMIE CHUCKLES]
[EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
SAM: Mind your backs, boys.
Coming through!
Tea time.
Tea time. Well done today.
Great stuff.
Chop chop before it gets dark.
JAMIE: It's waitin'.
Alphas aren't like the others.
Not just bigger. Smarter.
SPIKE: What are we gonna do?
Well, we're not fighting it.
I've got no arrows left.
And anyway...
I've seen it take a dozen hits to drop one of those things.
So, we'll wait, too.
I'm really sorry, Dad.
What? What about?
This is all my fault.
- I couldn't hit anything.
- What are you talking about?
I tried but I was too scared.
And I kept missing.
What are you talking about?
This is not your fault.
And you kept shooting.
I've seen adults who canna get an arrow in the bow,
they're shaking so hard.
Not you. Hey, hey, hey...
Spike, you did well.
Honestly.
SPIKE: We're gonna miss the low tide.
JAMIE: Yeah. Yeah.
SPIKE: Aren't we?
There'll be another.
Hey, look out to sea.
Here.
Just there.
Quarantine patrol.
Probably French.
[DISTANT CRIES]
Dad...
What's that?
[SIGHS] Fire.
Something's burning?
JAMIE: Yeah.
Something.
Is it another village?
Nope.
What is it then?
I don't know.
I've never been there.
SPIKE: Does it always burn?
I just said
I've never been there, Spike.
[CRICKETS CHIRPING]
[SERENE CLASSICAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
[GAGGING AND GRUNTING]
Spike.
There she is.
Spike, I'm drowning.
[RUMBLING]
[SERENE CLASSICAL
MUSIC CONTINUES]
Get out! We gotta get out!
Oh, fucking hell.
Get up! Get up, Spike!
Get your bum down.
Wake up, we've gotta move!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
It's all right, son.
It's all right.
Aah! Fuckin' hell!
[SPIKE COUGHING]
What happened?
Old building.
I dunno.
Chimney fuckin' died on us.
The noise will bring 'em.
We gotta move.
SPIKE: Is it low tide?
JAMIE: It'll be low enough.
We move fast but quiet.
If you see the Alpha, just run straight
for the causeway and over it. All right?
You stop for nothing! Go on!
- Where will you be?
- Right behind you.
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- [PANTING]
JAMIE: No sign of the Alpha.
SPIKE: It's still high tide.
JAMIE: Only just.
The water will be shallow.
But we can make it.
Shin-deep.
We're good. All right.
Take your boots off.
Aye. Line up the gates.
That's our path.
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- It's okay. Just breathe.
Here. Let's go.
You go first.
[SERENE CLASSICAL
MUSIC PLAYING]
Go on, son.
[PANTING]
[BIRDS CHITTERING]
[GROWLS SOFTLY]
[CHUCKLING]
How about that day, Spike, eh?
First time to the mainland.
First kill. First run-in with the infected.
[PANTING]
Saw an Alpha! [CHUCKLES]
And missed the tide.
SPIKE: I've got so much to tell Mum when we get back.
[JAMIE WHOOPING, ECHOES]
[WHOOSHING]
[SERENE CLASSICAL
MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
- [DISTANT PANTING]
SPIKE: Dad.
Run, Spike!
Run!
- [SPIKE SHOUTING IN PANIC]
- Go! Go, keep going!
Keep moving!
- Oh! Oh, God! Get up!
- Dad, I can't!
- I can't!
- Spike! Get up, now!
Spike, go! Go, go, Spike!
Fucking go!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
SPIKE: I can't!
JAMIE: Yes, you can!
Oh, shit!
[ALPHA GROWLS]
JAMIE: [DISTANTLY] Incoming!
Open up!
[SERENE CLASSICAL
MUSIC RESUMES]
- [WHISTLE BLOWING]
- Help! Jenny! Jenny!
ANTHONY: Wakey, wakey!
Up, up, up!
Incoming!
- Wakey, wakey, boys.
- JENNY: Ant, who is it?
- Everyone up! Eyes on!
- Form up, boys! Get ready!
ANTHONY: Eyes on, eyes on!
JAMIE: Incoming!
[WHISTLE BLOWING]
Alpha!
Open up! Fucking open up!
Alpha! Alpha!
ANTHONY: Fuckin' Alpha, get that light on!
Keep the fuckin' light on him!
JENNY: Fire!
JAMIE: Get down!
[GROWLING]
[ROARS]
JAMIE: Go, go, go, go, Spike!
Go, go.
ANTHONY: Keep that fuckin' light on him.
Load it, load it, load it!
JAMIE: Oh, fuck.
This is it, Spike.
Breathe!
[GROANS]
Shit! Oh!
[SINGING] Oh me lads, you should've seen us gannin'
Passing the folks along the road
Open up!
Just as they were stannin'
All the lads and lasses
- There all wi' smilin' faces
- Jenny! Open the fucking gate!
- Gannin' along
- Wait.
The Scotswood Road
JAMIE: No, fucking open up!
Fuck's sake!
- Wait.
- No.
- Fuckin' hell, Jenny!
- SPIKE: Please, please.
- JAMIE: We're fuckin' good.
- Wait.
Look at me fuckin' eyes,
- we're clean.
- Wait.
[VOCALIZING]
Look at him.
- Look at his eyes!
- Jenny.
- He's clean! We're clean!
- Jenny, please.
All right, open up, let them in.
Go. Go.
To see the Blaydon Races
- [SONG ENDS]
- [ALL CHEER]
CROWD: [CHANTING]
Spike! Spike!
Spike! Spike! Spike!
Hey!
There were 25, 'bout 30 yards.
Tall grass. Wind.
[CROWD EXCLAIMS]
And where does that arrow go?
Right through his fuckin' neck!
[ALL CHEERING]
That fat bastard, he stands up
and lets out one of them girly screams...
[IMITATES SLOW-LOW'S SCREAM]
and then drops like a sack of fuckin' shite.
[CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
Next thing, we've got eight fuckin' infected...
Dad, swearing.
...running right at us!
[CHEERING]
I'm thinking, "Oh, shit, here we go."
Benny Big Bollocks here is just fuckin' taking shots.
[LAUGHING]
PEOPLE: [SINGING]
She stood there laughing
- No, I kept missing 'em.
- JAMIE: Nah, you didn't.
He's humble.
- Our humble Spike.
- I felt the knife in my hand
And she laughed no more
The fuckin' giant killer!
[CHEERING]
My, my, my Delilah
Why, why, why, Delilah?
Go on. Go on, go.
So before they come
To break down the door
Forgive me, Delilah
I just couldn't take any more
I gotta go.
[PEOPLE VOCALIZING END NOTE]
[BOISTEROUS CHEERING
AND SHOUTING]
[PANTING]
JAMIE: In here.
Go on, Rosey.
[ROSEY GIGGLING]
What... What are you...
What are you taking us here for?
[BOTH PANTING]
- BOTH: Oop.
- [ROSEY LAUGHS]
JAMIE: Oh, Rosey.
[BOTH PANTING]
Oh, fuck. [MOANS]
Oh, Rosey.
[BOTH CONTINUE PANTING]
[BOTH MOANING]
[MUFFLED CREAK]
[MUFFLED THUMP]
[GROANS]
Oh.
Spike.
I didn't expect to see you until past midnight.
Just came to see me mum.
How was she? She all right?
She's better than all right.
We were up and about.
We walked to the fields.
She's got a lotta life in her when she's not having a turn.
But what about your day? Eh?
More to the point.
Dad's made it out to be something it's not.
Like what?
Like I'm a hero.
I expect you are, to him.
Just feels like he's lying.
So what did happen out there?
- I shot one of the fat ones.
- Ah.
- It was hardly moving.
- [LAUGHS]
But then we got chased by some of the fast ones,
and I couldn't hit a thing.
Then we just hid until it got dark.
I was just scared.
Felt sick.
I wanted to be home with me mum.
Your dad probably felt the same.
[SCOFFS]
Tell you what, though, never seen so much land.
- Mm.
- It was so big.
What did you see?
Well, hills...
Forests...
And a fire.
A fire?
I wonder if you saw old Kelson.
Didn't imagine he was still alive.
Was it southwest?
Christ. That'll be Kelson.
[EERIE SCREECH]
Believe it or not,
he used to be my GP
some 30 year back.
- What's a GP?
- A doctor.
- A doctor?
- Aye.
Had his practice just outside Whitley Bay.
Dad said that he didn't know what the fire was.
And he says all the real doctors are dead.
That's why no one knows what's wrong with Mum.
Just feels like he's lying about everything.
Nah. You know what?
[SAM SIGHS]
He probably didn't wanna spook you.
Dr. Kelson is...
odd.
How is he odd?
What's so special about the fire?
If your dad doesn't wanna talk about it,
I don't think I should.
Why don't you go back to your party? Eh?
I'm fine here wi' your mum.
No.
You go.
I'll look after her now.
Okay.
[BOTH CHUCKLE]
Got ya. [CHUCKLES]
SPIKE: They're all lying, Mum.
[ROOSTER CROWING]
[ISLA BREATHING HEAVILY]
Spike, will you go to the shops for us?
I need some Nurofen.
Nurofen?
It's me head. It's just...
[PENSIVE EERIE MUSIC PLAYING]
[GROANS]
Never mind. It doesn't matter.
- [DOOR OPENS]
- JAMIE: Hello!
ISLA: We're up here, love.
Well, that was some party.
Absolute carnage.
- [GROANS]
- You look...
You look like you've been
dragged through a hedge backwards.
JAMIE: Maybe I did.
I woke up in a wheat field.
And where did you disappear to, Spikey?
Looked around and the guest of honor had vanished.
Just came home.
Hey, giant-killer.
[DOOR OPENS, CLOSES]
[PENSIVE EERIE
MUSIC CONTINUES]
I'll make some breakfast.
What's going on, Spike?
Why didn't you tell us there was a doctor
that could see Mum?
Doctor?
We don't have a doctor.
Haven't had a doctor here in forever.
Dr. Kelson, Dad.
The fire. On the mainland.
Who've you been talking to?
[SIGHS] So he is a doctor.
Was it Sam?
Bloody fool.
Putting ideas in your head.
He's not a doctor, Spike.
Maybe he once was. Years ago.
But he's long since gone insane.
What do you mean?
Is he a doctor or not?
Before you were born,
we used to forage.
But it got harder, you know,
so you'd have to travel further.
And one day, it took a group of us close to Kelson's.
Right?
Aye. 500 yards out,
we started to smell death.
Now understand, we were well used to that smell.
Back then, the dead were everywhere.
But this...
this was totally different.
This stench was like...
it was like a wall.
You could touch it.
And we got to the brow of this hill,
and we looked down...
[JAMIE SCOFFS]
I've never seen anything like it.
[EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Corpses.
Hundreds.
[MUSIC SWELLS]
Just arranged in lines.
Men, women, children.
And in the middle, was this fire.
Stood by it, was Kelson.
For some unfathomable purpose,
he'd dragged all the bodies there.
And a few seconds later,
he turned around and he looked right at us
and he waved.
Casually, like, "Hey. Wanna come down, lads?"
Yeah. We turned and ran.
And in 15 years,
none of us have been back.
Like I said.
Insane.
[SOFT CRACKLING]
Oh, fuck. [SIGHS]
Do you want Mum to die?
'Course I don't.
Ah, Spike, what sort of question is that?
What's really wrong with her?
[SIGHS]
I don't know.
Is she dying?
JAMIE: I don't know.
I think she's dying.
And so do you.
If she dies,
are you gonna be with Rosey?
Watch your mouth.
What would her Davey think about that?
I said, watch your bloody mouth!
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Son...
ISLA: Jamie!
Spike!
[DOOR CLOSES]
[ISLA MOANS]
Oh, it's pounding, Spike.
Pounding.
I know, Mum. I'm sorry.
[SPIKE SNIFFLING]
Need some water, love?
I'll go get you some.
Get the fuck away from us.
"From us"?
[PANTING]
You heard us.
Just go away, Dad.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[PANTING]
- [WIND WHISTLING]
- [SEAGULLS CALLING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
SPIKE: There's a fire!
There's a... Run!
ANTHONY: Fuckin' smoke, look.
SPIKE: Ant, Mark!
- There's a fire!
- Go, go, go on! Go on!
SPIKE: There's fire in the main barn!
You've got to go!
I can't leave the gate, Spike.
SPIKE: You have to.
That's why they sent me.
I'll be on the siren.
But you've gotta go now.
They need every man, they said!
- Go!
- For fuck's sake.
SPIKE: Hurry. Go.
ANTHONY: Fuckin'...
Keep your eyes on the horizon.
And stay on that siren!
MAN: Gonna get more water!
WOMAN: Fetch more water!
MAN: Fire!
WOMAN: Get more water. Go!
[CLAMORING]
[SPIKE PANTING]
Come on, Mum. Let's go.
MAN 1: Get water! Water!
MAN 2: Get some more water from the sea!
ISLA: Where are we going?
The beach.
And the fields.
- We're going to the beach?
- Yeah.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
ISLA: This is the mainland.
SPIKE: Yeah.
ISLA: But we can't...
We can't be on the mainland.
It's too dangerous. It's...
- It's okay, Mum.
- No.
- I know how to keep us safe.
- No, no, no, this isn't right.
It's not right. Where's...? [PANTING]
Jamie?
Where's...
Where's Dad?
- Dad's not here.
- Then we...
Then we have to go back now.
Back home.
We have to run, or we...
Mum...
We can't go back. Tide's in.
Oh, God.
Going to see a doctor.
What? A doctor?
- A real doctor.
- No.
From the old days.
Something wrong with you, Mum.
The doctor's gonna make you better.
Okay?
Okay.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[PANTING TIREDLY]
Okay, Mum.
We'll stop here for the night.
We'll stay there.
- [WIND BLOWING]
- [BIRDS CHIRPING]
[RAIN PATTERING ECHOES]
[ISLA CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Is your dad silly?
- Dad?
- Yeah.
Silly with ya. Jokey.
Your granddad was so silly.
You wouldn't believe how much.
Everyone else thought he was so serious...
but around me, he was daft.
Is your dad like that...
you know, when it's just the two of you?
No.
ISLA: Just wanting to make sure you're tough enough.
Like him.
You know, when I look in your face...
I see your granddad's eyes.
It's nice.
[BOTH LAUGH]
Exactly.
[GRUNTS]
You should get some sleep.
I'm gonna stay awake.
Keep watch.
Okay, Dad.
[RAIN PATTERING CONTINUING]
[CROWS CAWING]
[CAWING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOFT GROWLING]
[MUSIC SWELLS]
[SPITS]
[GROWLS]
[GROWLING HOARSELY]
[GASPING]
What?
What happened?
I don't know.
SPIKE: Here.
Gotta go.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [GRUNTS]
- [THUDDING]
[ANIMALS CHITTER]
[GROWLING ECHOES]
- [SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
- [SOLDIER SHOUTING IN SWEDISH]
- [BONES CRACK]
- [SOLDIER SCREAMS]
[SOLDIER SHOUTING IN SWEDISH]
[SCREECHING APPROACHING]
[INFECTED SCREECHING]
[SOLDIERS SHOUT IN SWEDISH]
[SCREECHING, GROWLING]
- [PANTING]
- [SCREECHING]
[GROWLING]
[VOMITING]
[SCREECHING, GROWLING]
[SOLDIERS SHOUT IN SWEDISH]
[SOLDIERS PANTING]
[SCREECHING]
[PANTING]
[SPEAKING SWEDISH] Ugly fuckers.
Okay, move back.
[OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOLDIERS BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
- [SOLDIERS GASP]
- [ROARING]
- [SCREAMS]
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[SOLDIER SHOUTING IN SWEDISH]
[ROARING]
[MUSIC FADES]
[SCREAMS]
[SCREECHING, GROWLING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[IN ENGLISH] Oh, look.
The Angel.
[SERENE MUSIC PLAYING]
Do you remember the first time you showed me the angel, Dad?
We drove near here.
Left the car.
We walked until we spotted it rising over the treetops.
You said it would stand like this forever.
Like the pyramids.
Or Stonehenge.
So when you look at it, you...
You're seeing into the future.
Do you remember that day?
I couldn't have been more than, what, seven or eight?
Us two are real-life time travelers, you said.
[FATHER SIGHS]
Fallen into the future.
And I got...
I got scared.
Because I thought you were being serious
[LAUGHS] and we really had.
How many hundreds of years have we fallen this time?
Is it thousands or more?
Mum?
Spike.
Your nose is bleeding again.
[HOARSE GROWLING]
Keep still.
Don't move.
- [HOARSE GROWL]
- [GASPS]
[SCREECHING]
No, no, no!
Wait! Don't blink!
You're fine.
[SCREECHING, GROWLING]
Shit. Come on, Mum!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Keep going, Mum!
Don't stop!
[SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
Run! Run!
Don't stop, Mum! Get in!
Go, Mum, go!
[GROANS]
SPIKE: Get inside! Get inside!
Get inside!
Fuck! Fuck!
[ISLA WHIMPERING]
- [GAS HISSES]
- Go! In! Get in!
[BOTH COUGHING]
Spike, I can't breathe.
Spike, it's gas!
- Can't breathe!
- No, Mum!
- Don't...
[THUDDING]
[ALL GASPING, COUGHING]
Get off her!
Spike...
Spikey!
Get off her!
[MUSIC SWELLING]
[GASPS]
[COUGHS, GASPS]
SOLDIER: [GRUNTS]
Get down! Now!
Go on!
[GROANS]
[WHOOSHING]
[GRUNTS]
[GASPING ECHOING]
[INFECTED SCREAMING]
[PEACEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPUTTERING]
[GRUNTS]
- [TINNITUS RINGING]
- [VOMITING]
[COUGHING]
[ISLA GASPING]
What happened?
[SNIFFLES]
Benzene.
Vaporized.
Built up over the years.
[COUGHING]
Oh.
I'm Spike.
And this is me mum.
I'm Erik.
[COUGHS]
[GROANS]
ERIK: What's wrong with her?
SPIKE: I don't know.
I'm taking her to a doctor.
Right.
What happens now?
What do you mean?
ERIK: Well, you live here, don't you?
On this fucking island.
You're a... You're a native.
- A native?
- ERIK: [SHOUTS] Hey,
what the fuck happens now?
Do more infected come?
I don't know. Probably.
They would've heard the noise.
ERIK: Of course, they'll come.
The bärsärk will come.
They'll rip
our fucking heads off.
Do you understand?
[GROANS]
- You're not from here.
- Will you shut her up, please?
- [GROANS]
- Wait, where are you from?
I'm from Sweden, now can you make her shut up?
- She can't help it.
- She... She can't help it?
You can't help me?
Why the fuck did I help you, huh?
I could've saved my bullets!
[SPITS]
I gotta get outta here.
- I'm gonna leave.
- SPIKE: Well, you can go.
I'm not leaving her.
[SIGHS] Thank you, Daddy.
Jesus Christ. Can this get any more fucked up?
[WIND BLOWING]
[ERIK SIGHS]
Fuck's sake.
My best friend from school is a delivery driver.
You don't know what a delivery driver is.
He, um,
delivers packages.
You know, people order stuff online.
I bet you don't know what online is.
Uh, it doesn't matter.
He's a... He's a driver.
And I told him...
you're wasting your life,
Felix.
You only get one life, and you're pissing it away.
And he said...
"Yeah, what are you gonna do, fuck nuts?"
[RUSTLING]
So I joined the navy...
to prove a point.
Now who's pissing away their life, huh?
I don't understand what you're saying.
I'm saying I should have been a delivery driver.
Right now, I'd be stuck in traffic somewhere...
or driving too fast down a narrow street or something.
SPIKE: Then why are you here?
[SIGHS] My fucking boat sank.
We were patrolling on the east coast of Scotland
and we hit something.
[LAUGHS] Scotch on the rocks.
Doesn't matter.
Few of us found a life raft.
We didn't wanna make it to shore, obviously,
- but the wind blew us.
- [ISLA GROANS]
Eight of us made it to land.
Now I'm the only one left.
Will you be rescued?
[BIRD SCREECHING]
You do know the whole island is in quarantine, right?
What do you think the patrol boats are for?
Well, I know there's a quarantine.
But I thought it was only for us.
Quarantine is for any poor fucker
who puts one toe on this island.
You hit land, you never leave.
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
You can come to my town.
After I take my mum to the doctor.
Yeah, where is this doctor?
There.
Not far.
[SCOFFS] "Not far"?
Hey, hey, you try carrying your mother around for a bit.
I'm gonna take a break.
First meal in a day and a half.
Have another.
Seem to really like apples.
Yeah.
One percent.
No signal.
What's that?
Soon, it's a brick.
But for a few more moments it's...
something like a radio.
But with photos.
Do you have radios?
Do you have photos?
Some people have old ones.
ERIK: There.
Take a look at that.
That's a new one.
It's my fiancée.
Or ex...
I guess.
What's wrong with her face?
What do you mean?
She looks weird.
ERIK: You're weird.
She's gorgeous.
What's wrong with you?
SPIKE: Tsk. I know what it is.
There's this girl in my town who has the same thing.
ERIK: Thing?
She's allergic to shellfish.
So, if she eats scallops, then her whole mouth
- gets dead fat and swells up.
- Give me that.
[SIGHS]
ERIK: Yeah, there it goes.
[SPEAKING SWEDISH]
[IN ENGLISH]
Don't hook up with Felix.
[THUDS]
Dad...
I'm cold.
Why does she call you "Dad"?
That's weird.
I mean, I'm sure there's a lot of inbreeding
around these parts...
but this seems unlikely.
She's just confused.
She wasn't always like this.
Most of the time she's just like she always was.
Who's like she always was?
You, Mum.
Oh.
Who are you?
I'm Erik.
And this is your father,
Spike.
[CHUCKLES]
- What?
- [ERIK LAUGHS]
- He's just being silly, Mum.
- He's being a dick.
- [LAUGHS]
- Mum!
Sorry.
He saved our lives.
I know a dick when I see one.
God, remind me where we're going, again?
SPIKE: The doctor.
Right. Okay.
ISLA: Well, let's go.
Mum...
ERIK: She can walk?
[WIND BLOWING]
Why do they get so huge?
The bärsärk.
[SIGHS] Well, Sam says, on some...
the infection kinda works like steroids.
Yeah?
I mean, I don't know what steroids are.
I'm guessing that's what turns them Alpha.
ERIK: Alpha. You make them sound like stock brokers.
Or fucking Wall Street guys.
What?
You know what bärsärk is?
Bärsärk is better.
It's like...
[GROWLS] Crazy fucking
Viking warrior. You know?
I'm actually a Viking.
Maybe if I get infected,
I'll turn into one.
[SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
ERIK: What the fuck was that?
SPIKE: I don't know.
[SCREAMING CONTINUES]
No, no, no. Hey, hey!
Where are you going?
I'm not leaving her.
Hey!
[SCREAMING IN DISTANCE]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CHITTERING]
[SCREECHING]
- [SCREECHING]
- [THUDDING]
[SCREAMING]
Mum!
- [GASPING]
- [INFECTED STRAINING]
[STRAINING]
[SCREAMING]
[SPIKE GRUNTING]
[SOFT SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
SPIKE: Mum!
- Spike, wait!
- Oh, fuck.
Mum, what are you doing?
ERIK: Stop!
SPIKE: Don't touch her.
[INFECTED SCREAMING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[SCREAMING]
[ERIK SPEAKING SWEDISH]
[INFECTED BREATHING HEAVILY]
[STRAINING]
[IN ENGLISH]
Fucking shit! Holy fuck, shit.
[GROANS]
ERIK: What are you doing?
Fucking drop her.
[SOFT SURREAL MUSIC CONTINUES]
[ISLA BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [BABY COOING]
- ISLA: Cut it, Spike.
Spike, cut it.
SPIKE: Right. Where?
Here.
No fucking way.
[SPIKE GRUNTS]
- Water.
- Yeah. Here.
[CRIES]
ERIK: What the actual fuck?
SPIKE: Wash your hands.
ERIK: What the fuck?
- [CRYING]
- What the fuck?
You're all insane.
- [COOING]
- [GASPING]
ISLA: Here. Well done, Spike.
[SCREAMS]
[SCREAM ECHOES]
- [BABY CRYING]
- [EXCLAIMS]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
[PANTING]
ERIK: Right.
Put it down.
Put it down!
- It's a baby.
- It's a fucking zombie baby!
Just put it down. [SPEAKS SWEDISH]
We can't let these fuckers breed.
We need to kill it!
It's a little girl.
[GRUNTS]
Put it on the fucking ground!
- She doesn't look infected.
- She's not infected.
If you don't put it on the ground right now...
- SPIKE: Look at her eyes!
- I'll kill you both!
- She's not infected.
- I'll kill all of you!
You got five seconds.
- Five!
- Get up, Mum. Move!
ERIK: Four!
Three!
- [ALPHA ROARING]
- [GASPING]
[ERIK SCREAMING]
No!
[ERIK SCREAMS]
- [THUDS]
- [ALPHA ROARS]
[INTENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [EXCLAIMS]
- Alpha.
[GROWLING]
Move, Mum!
- Move!
- Yeah. Right.
Shit. [PANTING]
[SHOUTS]
[GROANS]
Run, Mum!
[ISLA PANTING]
[EXCLAIMING]
[GRUNTS]
[GROWLS]
[ROARING]
- [PANTING]
- [ROARING]
[GRUNTS]
- [GROANS]
- [GRUNTS]
[PANTING]
[ROARING]
Mum! Get off the train!
- [SHOUTS]
- [GROWLS]
[GRUNTS, GROANS]
[ROARING]
Mum! Run to the smoke!
[ROARING, GROWLING]
Keep running! [GRUNTS]
[GRUNTS]
- [ROARING]
- [SPIKE SCREAMS]
- [BLOWS]
- [GROANS]
- [BREATHING HEAVILY]
- [SURREAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[SPIKE SCREAMING]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
[PANTING] Fuck.
[GASPING]
[ALPHA BREATHING STEADILY]
Morphine, xylazine.
[LAUGHING]
It's extremely fast-acting.
[GASPING]
Excuse my appearance.
I paint myself in iodine.
It's an excellent prophylactic.
The virus doesn't like iodine at all.
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Oh.
Think I'll take this, Samson.
Let... Let go.
[SAMSON GRUNTING]
I call this one Samson.
He's lived in the area a good three years now.
[LAUGHS]
I usually
keep my distance from him, of course. [EXCLAIMS]
- [KELSON LAUGHS]
- Sir...
"Sir."
Oh.
Such good manners. Huh.
Are you Dr. Kelson?
I am.
I'm Spike, and this is me mum, Isla.
Spike, Isla.
SPIKE: And this is a baby.
[SIGHS]
We need your help.
Come on, then.
We need to go before he wakes up.
[SIGHS]
SPIKE: What's that?
[LAUGHS]
I've been...
I've been waiting almost
13 years for someone to ask that question.
[LAUGHS]
I often thought
I would die here alone...
of age or starvation or violence...
never having had the chance to reply.
Do you know the words "Memento Mori"?
No.
It's Latin. Ironically, it's a dead language. [LAUGHS]
It means "Remember Death."
Remember you must die.
[PLEASANT SURREAL MUSIC
PLAYING]
[COOING]
This helps to keep them out.
KELSON:
There were so many dead.
Infected and non-infected alike.
Because they are alike.
Here, careful.
[PLEASANT SURREAL MUSIC
CONTINUING]
Every skull is a set of thoughts.
These sockets saw.
And these jaws spoke and swallowed.
This is a monument to them.
A temple.
[CLATTER]
- Sorry, sorry.
- Oh. [LAUGHS] Don't worry.
No, it's... it's not precious in that way. It's, uh...
- [DEEP BREATH]
- [BABY CRYING]
The structure is solid
but the bones will fall apart due to...
time, or the elements...
or Spike's hand.
The Memento Mori is...
is actualized.
Do you know this man?
His name was Erik.
He saved our lives.
All right, let's find Erik a home.
[WHOOSHING]
[EXCLAIMS]
[SOFT LULLABY MUSIC PLAYING]
[STEAM WHISTLING]
[BABY COOING]
[SOFT LULLABY MUSIC
CONTINUING]
KELSON:
Keep going, that's good.
Good lad.
Alas, poor Erik.
[LAUGHS]
Choose a place for him.
KELSON:
Very nice. Well done, Spike.
The baby is a newborn.
It was from an infected.
But she's not infected.
We took her from the mother.
How interesting.
The magic of the placenta.
I'd wondered if that might happen.
But she'll need milk.
Water will keep her alive for a few days at most.
Is that why you came to see me?
The baby?
No.
KELSON:
Take your right forefinger,
put it on your nose...
and from there, try and touch my forefinger here.
[INFECTED SCREECHING
IN FAR DISTANCE]
Okay.
[INFECTED SCREECHING
IN FAR DISTANCE]
Isla, it would be helpful if
I could check your breasts...
and under your arms.
Is that okay?
Is that tender?
Your feelings of confusion...
do they feel like episodes?
Phases?
Or does it feel more constant?
[SIGHS] It was waves, but...
I think the tide's coming in.
I asked you to remember a word.
Yes.
Do you remember what it was?
A word...
KELSON: Isla...
I have no diagnostic equipment...
and I can't take a biopsy.
But from what I can observe,
I think you have cancer.
It may have spread from your brain to your body,
or your body to your brain.
Either way, it has metastasized.
It explains your symptoms, and, I'm afraid...
the masses on your breasts and lymph nodes.
I... I am very sorry.
ISLA: When I'm confused,
I know I'm confused.
I feel surprised at meself, when I...
you know, when I say strange things.
But I say them anyway.
But not all of me is confused. [SIGHS]
I thought it might be cancer.
Didn't know how to tell you,
Spike.
I was too scared.
I needed someone else to tell you, but no one did.
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
I don't understand.
Are you saying you can't make me mum better?
I wish I could. But I'm afraid it's not possible.
SPIKE: What does that mean?
Is she gonna die?
Is the cancer gonna kill her?
Yes.
SPIKE: When?
KELSON: It's hard to say.
[SPIKE BREATHING SHAKILY]
Soon.
[SPIKE SIGHING]
Will it hurt her?
Spikey, me love.
Already hurts. [SIGHS]
This can't be happening.
Doctor, please, please.
You must be able to help her.
You need a medicine. One...
One of the old medicines from the hospitals.
If you tell us where one was I can...
- I can go, and I can get it.
- Spike. Spike. Listen to me.
Just tell us, please.
There is no medicine that can cure her.
[SIGHING]
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
Doctor... Doctor, please.
It was so hard to get here.
[BREATHING SHAKILY]
- So hard to find you.
- ISLA: Spike, come here.
Now he's saying we can't help it.
- Mum.
- Come on. Come on.
[SPIKE SOBBING]
- Mum...
- ISLA: Should've told ya.
- Should've told ya.
- [SOBBING]
[WHISPERS] Please...
Spike.
The doctor can't make me better,
but he can help me.
SPIKE: I don't understand.
ISLA: I do.
I want you to try and always remember that.
I understand.
[BLOWS]
SPIKE: Mum. Mum?
You're all right.
[SPIKE BREATHING SHAKILY]
Mum. Mum.
Shh. Just rest. It's okay.
Hey.
[SOFT EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING]
ISLA: Look who it is.
Spike...
Memento Mori.
What did it mean?
Remember we must die.
KELSON: And it's true.
There are many kinds of death...
and some are better than others.
The best are peaceful.
Where we leave each other in love.
You love your mother.
I love her.
And Isla, you love Spike.
So much. Mm.
Memento Amoris.
Remember you must love.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC BUILDS]
[ISLA SNIFFLING]
KELSON: Isla.
Come.
[SIGHS]
ISLA: Stay here with the baby.
- Mum?
- Love ya, Spike.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC BUILDS]
[SOFTLY] Mum?
[ISLA SIGHS]
[BLOWS]
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC BUILDS]
[SINGING SOFTLY]
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC SOFTENS]
KELSON: Spike.
Find a place for her.
The best one of all.
[SOFTLY] Mum.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC BUILDS]
[GRUNTING]
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC CONTINUING]
[KISSES]
[SIGHS] Love you, Mum.
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC SOFTENS]
[SNIFFLES]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[SIGHING]
[HEAVY FOOTSTEPS
RAPIDLY APPROACHING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [CLANGS]
- [SPIKE PANTING]
KELSON: Get in! Hurry!
- [CLANGS]
- Stay down.
[WHISPERS] Stay still.
[SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
[SAMSON GROWLING]
[BONES RATTLE]
- [CLANGS]
- [ROARING]
[GROWLING]
[ROARING]
- [CLANGS]
- [SAND RUSTLING]
- [CLANGING]
- [SAMSON GRUNTING]
[GROWLS]
[SILENCE]
- [SCREECHING IN DISTANCE]
- [PANTING]
- [ROARING]
- [KELSON GROANING]
[KELSON SHOUTING]
- [GROWLING]
- [GROANING]
- [KELSON GROANS MUFFLED]
- [SAMSON GRUNTING]
[GRUNTS]
[MUFFLED GROANS]
[GASPS]
[SPIKE AND KELSON PANTING]
[SIGHS]
Thank you, Spike.
[PANTING]
I think...
I think it's time for you and the baby...
to go home.
SPIKE: Yeah.
- [COOING]
- KELSON: That's it. There.
It's all right, darling.
[SAMSON SNORING]
[ANIMALS AND INSECTS CHITTER]
[WOOD CREAKING]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
[SOFT GLOOMY ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING]
[SPLASHING]
[SNIFFLES]
SPIKE: Dad.
I'm okay.
You don't need to look for me.
I'll come back when I'm ready.
I wanna keep walking...
until I can't see the sea.
[GLOOMY ROCK MUSIC BUILDS]
We found Dr. Kelson.
He's not insane.
He's a kind man.
[BABY CRYING]
- [BABY WAILS]
- ANTHONY: A baby?
JENNY: Come on!
ANTHONY: Yeah.
[BABY WAILING]
SPIKE:
The baby's from an infected...
but she's not.
She's okay.
JENNY: She was left just outside the gates.
[WAILING]
SPIKE: Please be kind to her.
Her name is Isla.
[GLOOMY ROCK MUSIC BUILDS]
[GRUNTING]
[SCREAMING] No!
Spike!
[ODD SHOUT ECHOES]
[ODD HOWL ECHOES]
JAMIE: [SCREAMS] Spike!
[GLOOMY ROCK MUSIC BUILDS]
[INFECTED GROWLS]
[GROWLING]
[GLOOMY ROCK MUSIC BUILDS]
[INFECTED SCREECHING]
Fuck.
- [GRUNTS]
- [GROANS]
[MUSIC FADES]
[PANTING]
MAN: Oh!
Wonderful shot.
It was real poetry.
Though, I think there's a few too many coming now.
[GROWLING ECHOES]
Even for a fine young warrior like yourself.
Would you mind if we stepped in?
It would be our pleasure.
[GROWLING APPROACHING]
All right.
Hold.
[GROWLING]
Fucking go.
[PUNK ROCK VERSION
OF TELETUBBIES THEME PLAYING]
[GROANS]
[LAUGHS]
[SHRIEKING]
[SCREECHING]
[LAUGHING]
[CHOKING]
[MUSIC FADES]
Howzat?
GANG: Howzat!
[LAUGHTER, CHEERS]
Hello.
My name's Jimmy.
Let's be pals.
[PROGRESSIVE ROCK MUSIC
PLAYING]
[UPBEAT INDIE ROCK MUSIC
[SOFT EMOTIONAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[EMOTIONAL MUSIC BUILDS]